matt@burythehammer.com http://www.burythehammer.com http://github.com/burythehammer

Matt Long

I specialise in the creation and deployment of automated testing frameworks, and bridge the often troublesome gap between software development and testing. I have worked on a variety of projects in government, media, human resources, and supply chain management. I was also a physics teacher, though those days are well behind me now!

I'm a big fan of open source and Agile style development, and consequently hold a strong belief that testing should be a core part of the development process - testing as a profession has so much to learn from how far software developers have come in the last decade or so.

My current testing tools of choice are Selenium, Cucumber, Gatling, and Capybara, and I tend to write code in either Ruby or Java. On the side, I also dabble in Ruby on Rails and Android development.

I also maintain an irregular blog at burythehammer.com on testing and other interests.

My expertise

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Java 8, Android, SASS, BDD, TDD, RSpec, Cucumber, Capybara, Selenium, Gherkin, Gatling, QTP/UFT, HP ALM, Jenkins, PostgreSQL, Agile (Scrum / Kanban)

Experience

QA Consultant at OpenCredo, London (2015 – current)

As a QA engineer, I am primarily concerned with the construction, development, and maintenance of automated test frameworks. Tools/frameworks I work often with are Java Spring, Selenium, and Cucumber-JVM, though it really depends from project to project!

Our specialism is using cloud based services to build software which can be scaled massively

and reliably. Our technology stack includes Mesos & Marathon to build scalable microservice architectures, NoSQL databases such as Neo4j and Cassandra to scale and compute huge data sets, and container based deployment methods such as Docker and Ansible.

QA at Sedex, London (Jan - Jul 2015)
 Responsible for maintaining and extending the CucumberJVM / Selenium test suite of Sedex Advance, a large scale application developed with a microservice architecture.

Consultant at Infuse Consulting, London (2012 – 2015)

Since graduating from my MSc, I've been a consultant for Infuse Consulting, an automated testing consultancy that primarily works with HP's test suites. I have taken on a number of varied roles, and flourished in all of them:

Automated Test Engineer at ITV, London (Jan - Jul 2015)

Working with the complete rebuild of the ITV Player website, I develop Cucumber/RSpec (Ruby) acceptance tests, Gatling (Scala) performance tests, as well as delivering a considerable amount of structure and research to a previously disorganised performance test effort.

- Lead Tester for useMango, London (September 2013 December 2014)
- Originally working as a tester, I was the choice to lead the testing of our brand new test management and creation tool. The team lacked a clear testing strategy and made poor use of its existing tools. I brought structure to the testing by introducing a clear test strategy, training materials and resources, as well as introduced automated testing and CI practices. I proposed a custom type of test that formed the bedrock of the deployment suite, by executing useMango's own tests against itself. I set up ALM to track the progress and deliver automatic and up-to-date reports to management. We were able to successfully deliver 3 major releases during my tenure, none with any significant defects.
- QA Engineer for a government project, Portsmouth (December 2012 June 2013) Developing automated scripts using HP's testing suite, primarily ALM and QTP (now UFT), with custom tools that we had developed. Took additional responsibility for test execution halfway through the project, from a senior colleague. This post required SC clearance.

Science Teacher at Lampton School, Hounslow (June 2009 – September 2010)

I took the GTP, the Vocational equivalent of a PGCE course, with significantly more direct

teaching experience and responsibility. This challenging but rewarding experience shaped me significantly, as it taught me how to manage people effectively and deal with stressful workloads. I taught science classes from ages 12-18 with a range of abilities and was responsible for all my own training.

Education and Qualifications

University College London, London (2011 – 2012)

MSc (Hons), Computer Science

Imperial College London, London (2005 – 2008)

BSc (Hons), Physics

The King's School, London (2003 - 2008)

A-levels: Mathematics (A), Physics (A), English Language & Literature (B)

AS Level: Further Mathematics (A)

Other Interests

Videogames, indiepop music, arthouse cinema, contemporary art, economics and current affairs.

References available on request.